You are wonderful
You are worthy oh Lord
The SCOAN Sunday Service
- Good morning, Church!
- Good morning.
Emmanuel to viewers all over the world.
Thank you for your time.
God bless you.
You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to believe that you are led here by the Holy Spirit.
Amen!
Can someone just come out and tell us how you were led here today by the Holy Spirit?
OK.
Clap for her.
You were led by what?
Husband.
Go and sit down.
Who was led by the wife?
You were led by your wife?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you look at your life today; it is just the way our foundation started.
The beginning always has key leg.
Even to pray...
The way you started your prayer affects the whole prayer.
The way you come to church seems to affect your presence in the church.
It is just like that.
Even the way we start our business; we just look at our colleagues, someone who is making it,
whose business is going well.
Because of that you now choose to do the same business, which is very bad.
"Ah, that man is making it" - you will now walk towards the man, "Please, I want to invest in the same business."
The business you know about not seems to be good.
You approach the man, "Please, tell me how you started your business."
Even your education...
What you study in the university is a result of education of somebody, who is a minister of finance,
someone who is secretary general;
you want to go on internet to know what kind of subject... because of that you choose a course.
You want to be like that.
The beginning is always just the foundation affecting us.
Even our marriages today – the cause of collapsing, divorcing is as a result of how we met.
So, the beginning is just like that; it affects the whole structure.
Just like that.
Look at the children we give birth to.
Many of our children today; we can't tell, control, instruct, teach them, tell them what to do.
They become masters in the house.
Because of the beginning; the way we brought them up - the upbringing - we spoiled them.
We are not allowing them to taste some of the hard, difficult times we had in the past.
"These are my children, they must enjoy life. I suffered so much in life..."
By the time children grow up with that, they will think that life is all about bed of what?
Roses.
Life is not like that.
You have to allow them to taste some of the difficult parts of life.
Our beginning is the cause of what we are going through today.
We talk of worshipping God; many of us begin to understand what it means to worship God.
God is Spirit and His worshippers must do so in what?
In Spirit and in truth.
But today; we never knew in the past...
We just go by the way our forefathers worshipped God – conventional.
It is there; the song to sing Him, how to do this...
Everything is in the syllabus; we are not allowing the Holy Spirit to inspire us.
Which area will the Holy Spirit inspire us
when everything we want to do is on the table, on the paper?
How will the Holy Spirit inspire us?
This virtually is our life.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Our life is full of copy – that is why we also, are copies.
Hardly will you see original or raw.
You cannot see raw again.
Material is what we are seeing.
Human beings have turned to material.
That is why we cannot invest, discover or bring a new thing to the world.
How will you?
You must be raw, original, the way God created you,
grow up and be inspired by your Creator.
From time to time you must be inspired by God
to change the world and be at the centre of your own world.
Are we inspired?
Everything about us today; your dress, hair, look...
We are sitting down, you are looking around to see the kind of attire - beautiful one.
When you leave here, you go to market and buy the same thing.
We leave here and go to be a copier.
You move around and see some posh cars, "This is a posh car. I think I need this vehicle.
Let me take the picture."
Copy, copy; we have become imitation of man, not imitation of God.
In religion, in Christianity, in our worship – imitation of man, not imitation of God.
In our walk - imitation of man, not imitation of God.
You learn how to smile.
The way you smile... - why can't you smile?
You see some of them; you can see the way he walks is not original, not real.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is just what is happening now.
This has virtually affected our children.
The new generation today seems to be copies.
That has affected our relationship with God.
We now take our faith as a hobby, a game.
When I move to people to attend to them and hear them talking, you know where they are coming from.
The Bible is our standard.
It is just one Bible and the Holy Spirit is just one.
All over the world, there is one Holy Spirit.
The Holy Spirit operating here is the same Holy Spirit over there and all over the world.
As if the Holy Spirit is different - there is so much trouble.
That actually convinces me that the world is coming to an end.
With what we are seeing - so much.
Where do we start from, when people are copies?
Everything about you...
You have to study books to know how to pray - a lot of things...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Until we turn to imitate God Almighty, our Creator, we will not stop lamenting.
That crisis, lamenting, and others...
No matter how much blessings you have, how strong you are.
Faith is of man’s heart.
Every Word of God is Spirit and life and will work in you when you attend and act upon it.
Take note of that, "Spirit and life".
Since it is Spirit and life, there is no imitation of man there.
If somebody comes out to give testimony and says, "Praise the Lord!", you say, "Hallelujah!",
"When I received my morning water, I sprayed it this way... and I received a big contract";
you quickly write it down, "I sprayed it this way..."
Now, you walk towards the morning water to receive your own.
When you get home, you look at the paper, "I sprayed it this way...",
"OK - my contract is coming."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Salvation is of man’s heart.
Relationship with God is of man’s heart.
OK, now, we are here today.
You have read your Bible and right from nursery we know what the Bible says.
“Forgive us as we forgive those who sin against us.”
That is the standard; there is no other.
“Forgive us as we forgive those..." who what?
"... sin against us."
It means, let go of all unforgiveness, resentment, anger, bad feelings toward anyone but have you?
And you are here today to pray.
You are expecting God.
“Forgive us as we forgive those who sin against us.”
That is the standard; take note.
It means, let go of all unforgiveness, resentment, anger, bad feelings towards anyone.
But have you?
No.
What kind of hypocrisy!
Where are we going then?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Even if you receive and you have not put behind bad feelings toward anyone,
you will still lose that blessing.
You can receive; you cannot go with that blessing.
At the time you need that blessing you will lose it.
It is the standard.
At the time you need this blessing, you will lose it.
"Give us this day our daily bread."
What is our daily bread?
"Forgive us as we..."
Already, you have committed yourself.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are here for prayer that comes from faith.
What is prayer that comes from faith?
Prayer that comes from faith heals the sick.
Prayer that comes from faith sets the captives free.
Prayer that comes from faith blesses the poor.
And if they have sinned, they will be forgiven.
That is prayer that comes from faith.
Tell your neighbour, “Prayer that comes from faith heals the sick.
Prayer that comes from faith sets the captives free.
Prayer that comes from faith blesses the poor.
And if they have sinned, they shall be forgiven."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is what we are here for.
We are not just care for prayer for needs; but prayer that comes from faith.
Before we start; you see - everything is calm.
You will see people...
You will now say, "This lady was with me; we talked. What is wrong with her?"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is prayer that comes from faith.
That is, prayer that comes from the heart.
- Prayer that comes from where?
- Heart.
Prayer can only come from the heart when your spirit acts upon the Word.
You want your prayer to come from your heart
but it is only when your spirit acts upon the Word
that you have the prayer that comes from the heart.
Prayer that comes from the heart is prayer that comes from faith because faith is of man's heart.
This heart consists of offence; you are full of offence.
Faith does not share the same apartment with anyone.
God cannot share the same apartment, the same heart.
But your heart is full of offence, unforgiveness, resentment and anger.
Your heart is full of bad feelings toward anyone.
Faith cannot share the same apartment with offence.
Faith cannot share the same apartment with unforgiveness.
Faith cannot share the same apartment with anger.
Faith cannot share the same place with bad feelings towards anyone.
So, what do you want to do now?
It’s either you choose faith or you choose offence.
It’s either you choose faith or you choose resentment or unforgiveness.
This is where we are now.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Prayer that comes from the heart – that is, prayer that comes from faith,
heals the sick, blesses the poor, sets the captives free.
If they have sinned, they will be forgiven – that is the prayer that comes from the heart.
Are you with me?
If they have sinned, and you are praying for them,
and the prayer comes from faith,
they will be forgiven instantly.
That is why you will be healed.
You cannot be healed without forgiveness because healing is for salvation of your soul.
If they have sinned, they will be forgiven instantly -
that is prayer that comes from the heart.
But your heart is full of offence, unforgiveness, anger, resentment, hurt and pain.
You may be right but we should not hold offence against anyone
because if you hold offence against anyone, it will imprison your heart.
Once your heart is imprisoned, you go nowhere – no relationship with God.
Can we just stand up and pour our hearts; if there is any pain of the past,
if there is any bad feeling towards anyone.
Right now, you can at this moment stand up and tell, "Lord Jesus".
Reconcile yourself.
Let go of all unforgiveness.
Let go of bad feelings towards anyone.
Let go of all resentment.
In Your presence I am content
In Your presence there is light
Expressions of Your love
Revelations of Your power and might
In Your presence I can bring a love song offering
I’m in the presence of my King
In His presence, there is nothing like unforgiveness, resentment, anger
or bad feelings towards anyone.
Freedom, breakthrough, clearance – in His presence.
Hallowed be Your name
Lord and Majesty
Divine authority
Hallowed be Your name
Lord and Majesty
Divine authority
Hallowed be Your name
Yes.
As a child of God, you are to walk majestically.
Offence causes fear – fear of breakthrough, fear of sickness, fear of isolation.
When you have an appointment, you will be afraid whether they will hold that appointment.
If you have a clearance and you are asked to come for clearance,
you will be afraid whether you will receive the clearance.
When you want to sleep, you will be afraid of nightmares.
When you want to pray, you will be afraid whether your prayers will be answered.
Fear has been holding people in bondage.
The way fear rules people -
if that kind of fear ruled me, I would run away from Nigeria, because of what you people had done to me,
because of what you had said to me, what you had done to me - there is nothing you had not done to me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Majesty
Worship His majesty
Unto Jesus
Be all glory honour and praise
Majesty Kingdom authority
Flows from His throne unto His own
His anthem reigns
So exalt lift up on high
The name of Jesus
Magnify come glorify
Christ Jesus the king
Majesty
Worship His majesty
Jesus who died now glorified
King of all kings
With fear we will continue to swallow our vomit.
Fear will make you swallow your vomit; you take your vomit back.
Look at many of us here today, "Over my dead body will I come to Synagogue",
but we are in the Synagogue.
No!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is fear.
What you say you would not do, you find yourself doing.
When you say you would not go, you find yourself going there, because of offence.
That offence in our heart causes fear.
When you hold offence, bad feelings towards anyone, whether the person is right or wrong,
whether you are right or wrong and somebody abuses or cheats you -
whatever anyone might have done to you and you hold bad feelings towards him -
you will continue to live a life of fear.
You know, you maybe right, and you know something is done to you,
and you know you are right, and you are holding bad feeling toward anyone...
When I say ‘anyone’ – the accused and accuser.
Holding bad feelings toward anyone – you will continue to live life with fear.
Fear robs us of our blessings.
You will not be able to give your best.
That is why we cannot give our best.
You are always afraid.
God is not of fear but of love.
Where are we going and what is the cause of this fear?
Bad feelings towards anyone.
Tell your neighbour, “What is the cause of fear? Bad feelings towards anyone.”
You say, "Ah, he cheated me. I will not forgive him. He is very bad. I helped him; he dooped me.
I loaned him money. Hear what this man is saying about me; he calls me thief, he embarrasses me."
Bad feelings towards anyone...
You continue to live a life of fear.
A life of fear is a life of destruction.
If you cannot believe a man you can see, is it a man you cannot see you will believe?
If you cannot believe what you can see, definitely, you cannot believe God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You don't believe yourself; when you dream, you have to see many people for interpretation.
Because you don't believe yourself; there is a promotion in that dream for you,
"Let me go and ask people".
Because you don't believe anything good can come from you.
You say, "My pastor, please, I dreamt about the promotion..." - because you don't believe yourself.
Where are we going?
How do we get out of this mess?
We get out of this mess by stopping holding what?
Offences.
Whether your offence is too big; I don't want to use word 'offence' again.
Simple: bad feelings towards anyone.
If you say that, you know it covers all.
For you to get there, where God promised you, bad feelings towards anyone – stop it!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You keep singing this song...
Leave it for God
Don’t worry yourself
Don’t cry no more
What is the meaning of that?
Bad feelings towards anyone; that is the meaning.
Somebody slaps you, you say, "Why do you slap me?"
And now, you hold offence; that is bad feeling towards...
Leave it for God.
I'm a good example of "leave it for God"; my name is "Leave it for God".
Prophet "Leave it for God".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is me for you.
I know what I'm doing.
You think I cannot fight?
My name is "Leave it for God".
I will just look at you and...
Sometimes, when it is too painful, I will say...
I will not allow this to affect my future.
The future is very clear – clear and bright.
Why should I allow anything to stain that future?
The only way they can stain it is to attack and insult you.
Your answer to that insult will stain the future.
Don't trade anything with what?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Don’t ever trade anything with the future.
Suffer now and enjoy tomorrow.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, please...
"Be patient for the future" - tell your neighbour.
That is the answer.
Be patient for what?
Future.
We are not patient for the future.
You are in a hurry.
"I will answer. No, I have to fight. I have to defend myself." - No!
A time is coming – your future will answer them.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Do you know the reason I said, “Be patient for your future”?
Because your future will answer them.
Unanswered questions – the future will answer.
There are many things, "How would you defend yourself? How would you answer?" - No!
If you can be patient, that future will answer your critics.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, “Be patient – your future will answer your critics.”
That is when God will set a table before you and every essential of life will be on the table.
The table will answer your critics but you are not patient for your future.
Future we are speaking of is not here or there; future is next.
An hour to come, a second to come.
Your life can change any moment from now.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When we say future, people think, "10 years; I cannot wait. I'm still a student, undergraduate,
I'm unemployed, I don't have job, I'm homeless. What kind of future again?
How will I arrange my future? I don't know where I'm going. What future this man is talking about?"
Future belongs to God and future is what we call mystery.
How it happens – you don’t know.
It's just this...
Can you count how many seconds?
Your future; next is this, next -this...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The glory – many have lost it.
We have to be frank.
We got it before and we lost it.
But God is merciful; don’t give up.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you have lost it, that is not the end.
Please, I want to leave you here.
In summary:
please, be patient for your future.
Your future will answer your critics.
Your future will answer your enemies.
Your future will answer your adversaries.
Because He lives
I can face tomorrow
All fear is gone
Because I know
He holds my future
My life is worth living
Just because He lives
Be patient for your future.
The evidence of coming of your future will make your enemy to surrender.
They will surrender.
The evidence is so powerful.
A stone which a builder rejected will become the real cornerstone.
That is the future.
They reject you and call you names because they don’t know what is about to come.
There is a mystery somewhere waiting.
Reject you; this is how God does it.
He always allows enemies and critics to embarrass because of what is coming.
Be patient for your future.
This is the time you should expect embarrassment.
This will prepare you for the future.
Embarrassment will prepare you for the future.
Name-calling will prepare you for the future.
Whatever you are going through is to prepare you for the future; be strong.
That is it.
So, what you are going through is to prepare you for the future.
Pleasure cannot prepare you; pleasure will destroy you more.
This is not the time to talk of pleasure.
You want to be strong -
you need much of hard times, less of good times to prepare you for the war.
Unless you have arrived.
Have you arrived?
No.
What are you talking about?
You have not yet arrived.
You are still struggling and striving.
This is the right time to go through what you are going through -
sickness, hardship, name-calling, rejection, isolation.
This is the right time.
They will prepare you for the future; you will become stronger.
Your struggles will make you stronger.
- Hallelujah.
- Amen.
Give thanks to God, give thanks to Him.
You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes.
Take note – be patient for your future.
Your future will answer your enemies.
Your future will answer your critics.
The evidence will be overwhelming!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you believe you are too old for the future I'm talking about; God is prepared to add more to your age.
Amen.
Begin right now to let go of all unforgiveness, bad feelings towards anyone.
Anyone means accused and accuser.
Bad feelings - "I have bad feelings towards this man. The man is wicked. The man has dooped me.
No, I don't want to hear his voice. That is his number - delete it."
It will imprison your spirit and you need a free spirit to relate with God,
to relate with the Holy Spirit because your spirit will join itself.
When your spirit is imprisoned, how will you relate with God?
From this moment, make yourself available.
In your heart first, settle yourself.
Even your critics will not know that you have forgiven, but your heart - you have nothing.
One day, when they come across you, they will know that you are for them.
You are not against.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is how you will begin to prepare for your future.
It is like someone, who is about to wed, and the celebration is next week,
but he is fighting people now.
They may likely kill him before that time.
They will likely kill him.
When you are celebrating; you know your celebration is next week,
anything like fight comes your way - you will know that it is a work of an enemy.
I will be wedding next week, "Look! This is a work of an enemy."
You stay cool and calm, because you know that something is about to come.
What is about to come is why the enemy is doing all this.
They want to destroy what is about to come.
That is exactly your future - your life.
What you are doing now; if you don't let go of all your unforgiveness,
one will likely be destroyed before the future comes.
One may not die, but one will be on the sick bed.
One may not die, but one will have a disease and sickness that will make the future not enjoyable.
One will not die but one would be in the prison yard.
A lot of things happened like that.
By the time the future comes, they say, "Oh, you are destroyed already."
We go to the future, not that the future comes to us.
Not that you sit down and say, "Future come!" - no, you will go to future.
With forgiveness, humility, love, faithfulness, you will go to the future.
Let someone say, “My future is coming!”
When you say your future is coming – your arrival, your settlement, your clearance.
Then, many will depend on you.
Many will depend on you, so many will depend on you.
My future is coming.
Let go of all offence.
If you don’t let go of all offence, it will affect that future.
Your future will continue to be postponed.
Don't be surprised; by the time one gets there, they will open the file and show you,
"You are a king but you spent all your life on the street.
You are a president of a country but you spent all your life at the garage.
You are destined to be very rich but you spent all your life begging on the streets" - you will just see it in the file.
They will be telling you what you are destined to do.
You are destined to be rich, to be president of a country, to be this, to be that,
but they will open the file, "Look at yourself; you are begging, you are a beggar."
You will say, "Ah!" - you will be very surprised, that what you were destined to do
is different from what you went to do.
Because of offence, fight, disagreement, bad feelings towards anyone.
There is no way God can communicate with you.
He can only communicate with you through your heart, your spirit
but your spirit is full of offence, unforgiveness, anger, resentment, bad feelings toward anyone.
This is why many people today, when they realize that there is no way to go because of bad feeling,
they join cults, secret societies; they can do anything.
So, please.
Begin to believe in God’s authority now because you believe so much in majority.
Get yourself right with God; you can now move with the majority.
TT ROBERT BEGIER 29/06/2018 RV Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 13/08/2018